Cam, uh, welcome to Chicago, first of
all.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Uh, so, uh, how did this
signing, uh, come about for you and how
have they told you how you fit into, uh,
the Bear system?
>> Uh, just having some talks with my
agent, you know, over the past couple
weeks, you know, with the Scotland
combine. Um, he just told me that that
the Bears were really interested in me
and they uh liked the way I I approached
the game, how I played the game. You
know, I'm not the biggest fella out
there. So, um, my ability to go be
physical, um, go play above my weight,
play above my height. Um, I go about
things in in the classroom, uh, with my
teammates dayto day. And how they think
I can fit is um playing a little bit of
everything like I did in Buffalo. Uh
some safety, some nickel, uh some dime,
you know, special teams as well. So, I
think my versatility uh really helps and
I think that will help this team as
well.
>> I was going to ask you about that. How
did you come by this uh versatility?
Like what led to you uh trying different
positions?
>> Uh starting trying to stick around in
the NFL to be completely honest with
you. Uh I was undrafted coming out of
Buffalo. Um, I'm just trying to find a
way to stay on the team uh when I was in
Buffalo and cross trainining was brought
to me as an opportunity and so I just
took the opportunity and kind of ran
with it just trying to learn as much
football I could. Uh, I've been I was in
that Buffalo system for seven years so I
knew the whole defense at the back of my
hand. So, it helped me um really
understand the ins and outs of NFL
defenses and going against different
offenses offensive schemes. Sean.
>> Yeah. Hey, Cam. Welcome to Chicago. Um,
what is this moment like for for you and
your family? I mean, Buffalo has been
home for a long long time now.
>> Yeah, it's uh it's very exciting. I'm uh
very grateful for the opportunity. Um
from originally from Detroit, so not too
far away from home and uh a lot of my
family's been giving me some some uh
hate for signing with the Bears, but I'm
I'm telling like uh we're rivals now.
Uh, this is our division to win. So,
it's been pretty cool. I'm grateful for
the opportunity.
>> Adam,
>> hey, Cammy, you mentioned all these
positions that you've played over the
years. Do you have like a a favorite
one? Is there one in particular that you
think you excel at more more so than the
others?
>> Um, honestly, I like safety a lot. Um,
but I really wouldn't put it that much
higher than everything else. Like I like
nickel because like you get to be around
in the box a little bit more around the
football a lot. Same with the dying
position. But safety in the back end,
you just you just see everything a
little bit better. You able to go um
attack the ball when that ball is in the
air and then come down and kind of lay
some hits, you know? I'm not afraid to
throw this 190 93 pounds in in the mix,
man. So, uh not worried about that. So,
it just wherever I'm able to fit in and
and play is the position I like at the
most uh at the moment, you know.
>> Pat,
>> hey Cam, how are you? Um, what is it
like going somewhere new and I I know
you were just talking about your family,
but you know, just being in an
unfamiliar place.
>> What's the last time you had to do that?
>> College. Yeah,
>> let's say what
>> 2015. Yeah, 2015. So, I've been in
Buffalo for I say 10 almost 11 years.
So, uh it's different, but
um I try to embrace being uncomfortable,
you know. Uh you don't want to be
comfortable uh your whole life. You want
to try new things, new opportunities.
So, I'm I'm just trying to embrace it,
you know, take it a day at a time. Uh
get to know my new teammates, get to
know my new coaches, explore Chicago. um
a little bit and um yeah, like I said,
just a just very excited, grateful for
the opportunity and uh I just can't wait
to get started.
>> What are the pluses and minuses of going
to college in the same place where you
then play professionally?
>> Man, somebody just asked me that same
question.
>> I'm sorry.
>> No, you're you're fine. uh it wasn't on
here but um pluses is like you know the
area you know the fan base you know how
die hard you know Bill's Mafia could be
but any negatives I think was just I was
hoping I could venture off and you know
go to a new new place new city but uh
Buffalo is like my second home man I've
been there uh like I said 10 11 years I
got married there I had all three of my
kids there so that was a special place
in my heart, but it's time for something
new and I'm excited for it.
>> Sean,
>> when you play, you know, being able to
play all these different positions, what
is that preparation process like for you
just to kind of stay up on on all the
different assignments and and whatnot.
>> It's uh it's a lot of studying for sure.
Uh you got to put in a lot of hours. Uh
cuz week to week you can be asked to do
different things. You know, the game
plan changes and things of that nature.
So, um it's just a lot of a lot of film
watching, a lot of meetings with
coaches, uh just so you feel
comfortable. You don't want to go out
there and and uh not know what you're
doing cuz you won't be able to play
fast. So, the more questions you get
answered, the more film you watch, the
more comfortable you get, uh what
they're trying to ask you to do that
week and you can go out there and play
fast.
>> Last one, Adam.
>> Cam, you're joining a team that that's
got Caleb Williams at quarterback.
Obviously, you just played with with
Josh in Buffalo. Um, what's it like
being on a team a as a quarterback kind
of comes into a zone, becomes a star,
superstar, and and becomes one of those
top-notch quarterbacks in the league?
Like, what's that like to to be a part
of to be a teammate of his?
>> Uh, it's amazing so far. Um, just seeing
what he's been doing over the past
couple years, been watching from afar,
it's like, dang, if I had a chance to
play with him, that's like uh that'd be
really good. But um anytime you have um
superstar quarterback, a great
quarterback, you just know that you have
an ability to win every game. Like even
on defense, you can't. Sometimes you
don't play your best. It's like any
given Sunday, you know, everybody's not
going to be perfect, but you know, with
18 back there, uh under that center
slinging that rock, we got a chance to
win this game. So, um just feeding off
him. You know, he scored some points. We
try to get him the ball back. That's the
biggest thing. Just uh do what we can do
to help him. uh get the ball back and
score most most points he can.
>> Yeah. And you felt that and you lived
that in Buffalo with with Josh, right?
>> Correct. Yes. Most definitely. You know,
uh and then you you can see the ability
of your quarterback um being able to
take over games. It's like, oh,
everything is going right. And that's a
great feeling to be a part of. Like, I'm
glad he's on my team and I'm not going
against him. And I feel like that's the
same thing that's excuse me about to
happen here with Caleb. So, I'm excited.
Thank you.
>> Awesome. Thanks so much.
>> Thanks, guys. I appreciate it.
>> Hey, Contavis. How are you?
>> I'm good. How are you doing?
>> I'm good. Uh what how was this defense
sold to you? What's your interpretation
of what this thing's supposed to look
like and what your role will be in it?
>> Uh so, uh Jay-Z JG, Coach JG, uh goes
way back for me. um he has familiarity
with my uh longtime Dline coach uh Ryan
Nielson and he's trying to blend uh
coach Nielson's uh system with uh the
casur the attack scheme and uh I've been
blessed enough to be in both systems. So
I'm I'm kind of a blend of both things.
So I I I can kind of um put a vision out
of what he wants the the defensive
fronts to be. So, uh, that's somewhat my
role to just like come here and be like
the I wouldn't say the standard, but
like what he wants the D line room to be
like a blend of both cultures. Not so
much, uh, on the line of scrimmage, but
not just running up the field, you know.
You know, we want to attack blocks, uh,
knock them back, play on their side of
the line of scrimmage, really disrupt
plays, and, uh, rush the passer, you
know, while playing as we play the run,
you know, play the run on the way to the
passer. So, uh, uh, that's basically
what I've been sold as, uh, on the
defense and what they want me to do, you
know, just to, um, to, uh, blend both of
those systems and, you know, just help
this defense, uh, take a step forward.
>> Is that the part of your skill set that
fits here is the ability to do to do
both or what about your game do you
think makes you good at that? Uh, I
think I I think it like like you just
said, I think just being able to blend
both cultures together, you know, ever
since I left New Orleans in uh 2023, you
know, just uh
having to that refresher of playing with
coach Nilson, you know, his the
fundamentals, the perfectionist that he
is, you know, and been able to uh blend
that in with the speed and the
explosiveness that I have in my game,
you know, um I think it's it's helped me
to get a little bit better each year.
And um Coach Johnson was telling me he
feels like I just had one of my better
seasons last year. So I'm hoping I can
continue to build on that.
>> Bill,
>> thank you. Uh what do you think last
season in particular uh clicked for you?
And do you have a preference in terms of
uh what technique you play?
>> Honestly, as long as I'm on the field,
I'm happy. Um I think it clicked for me
just because um I was back in the
attacking system, you know. Um I had
been in systems that wanted attack to
attack or saying that they were going to
attack, but last year with Nate Ali, you
know, um coach, you know, um it's is
it's very similar to that Chris
Cassurich system where, you know, you're
you're getting off the ball, you're
you're getting in guys jaws, you know,
you're really knocking people back and
really like dictating what you want to
do, you know. Um, and uh, Coach Jay-Z,
you know, um, he that's what he wants to
do. He really doesn't want the offensive
line to dictate or the offense to
dictate what we do as a defense. He, um,
he wants us to control the line of
scrimmage and he really wants to, uh,
instill some fear in offenses, uh, going
forward this year. So, um, I think
that's why I had success, you know, that
the the mindsets, the uh, the thought
process. I It's something that I've
always wanted to do, something that I
really enjoy. It's early on in in my uh
NFL career like when I was in 49ers with
uh coach Casser, you know, it just I
just fell in love with that type of
scheme and I I have a lot of fun with
it.
>> And how how familiar are you with
Chicago andor any players on the team.
>> So I I have a little bit of familiarity
with Chicago. We actually just uh closed
on a home here, me and my wife, uh in
River Forest. So um we have very little
familiarity, but it's going to continue
to grow. Um, I know a couple guys on the
team. I know, um, well, I played briefly
with DeAndre Swift, played a full year
with Grady when he was with the Falcons,
and, uh, me and Garrett Bradberry. I
know he's a very new addition, but um,
we're we were in the same recruiting
class at NC State, the great NC State
University. And, uh, Joe Tuni was our OG
when we first came in. He was, uh, two
years older than us when we came in NC
State. So, I have some history with, uh,
a good bit of the guys here. So, I'm I'm
excited to come in. Um, from the moment
I stepped into the building on the
property, I've I've just been uh
overwhelmed with joy. Um, everybody here
has a smile on their face and I think
that speaks volumes because it shows
that, you know, it's not just a job for
him for for the people in the building.
You know, uh, everyone loves what they
do and I think they love who they're
working for. So, I mean, it's a it's a
great organization from top to bottom.
>> Adam,
>> two questions for you. A quick followup
on that. going back to to college. What
do you remember about going against
Garrett Bradberry and Joe Tuni in
practice? And what do you think of Joe
becoming one of the all-time greats at
his position?
>> Listen, this is this is a almost daily,
weekly, uh conversation about Tuni, man.
I mean, uh Tony was a specimen at state.
I mean, he had everything you want. He
had patience in his pass said, uh
quickness in his feet. Um he's sneaky
strong, too. Like a lot of guys see uh
Joe and he's like he's an undersized
guy. He's not overly like um I don't
brick in build, you know, like he's just
a he's a sneaky guy. So um from meeting
him at NC State and seeing everything
he's done in the league now, nothing
surprises me. I mean, he's just a hard
worker. Um he's not going to bring any
attention to himself. He loves up on his
guys. Um yeah, he's he's he's an amazing
guy. Um and then uh uh growing up and uh
just seeing everything that Bradberry's
done too, you know, from because um when
Brad uh when uh Garrett came into NC
State, he was a tight end and then he
spent some time as a three technique in
our Dline room and then he finally made
the transition over to offensive line.
It all clicked. So, I think that speaks
volumes for the athletic talent that he
is also, you know, and the um the uh
mental capacity he has as well, cuz you
know, from learning to be a tight end to
learning the the uh three technique uh
system with coach Nilson and then going
and learn the entire offensive playbook
as an offensive lineman, having to set
the protections, uh the mic, uh been on
the same level with the quarterback. I
mean, it's come on, man. That's that's
next level stuff. So, I mean, uh, AC
State does a great job of picking the
guys that they have in the building. So,
um, yeah, I mean, these guys are amazing
people.
>> All right, then. My next question is,
let's let's go back to 2022. Did Dennis
Allen is your coach, careerhigh in
sacks, career high in tackles, I think,
career high in QB hits. Like, what was
working with Dennis Allen at that point?
And then what was it like to to see him
again in the building today? I imagine.
>> I mean, it's amazing. It's uh it's super
exciting. Um I think that year with him
and coach Nilson was the first time I
really realized that I could blend both
systems. It didn't have to be full-time
attack. It didn't have to be fulltime
attack react, you know, I could really,
you know, um with the knowledge of the
playbook and being aware of what DA and
coach N wanted me to do in certain
situations and get certain backfield
sets, formation flips, you know, uh
stuff like that. just being able to have
the awareness to take advantage of those
times, you know, and um just really just
being able to to, you know, pin my ears
back and just be uh confident in the
player that I am. You know, they um they
really gave me a ton of opportunities to
just go out there and be who I was. So,
it's it's it's amazing.
>> All right, last one, Pat.
>> Okay, another followup. You just closed
on a house here. Were you going to move
here regardless or did you have a sense
you might end up here? What? Or or do
you just have a really good real estate
agent who got you closed in three days?
>> No. Uh, honestly, it's it's just a
blessing. Honestly, we were going to
Chicago regardless. Um, we just really
fell in love with the area. We get like
a a five, six day break between training
camp and the regular season. And last
year, we took the time to come up here
and we just fell in love with the city.
The food's amazing. The people are
friendly. The views of Lake Michigan. I
mean, it's what's not to like? I mean,
I'm I'm a little antsy about the winter,
but we'll get to that when we get to
that. Um, we just we just got lucky. And
then now look at us. We're part of the
Bears family, so it's it just worked
out.
>> Just happy coincidence.
>> Yeah.
>> That's cool. Thank you.
>> Awesome. Thank you so much.
>> No problem.